# LUIS LANDI

ux@luislandi.com

• +39 348 853 74 02

• <u>linkedin.com/in/luislandi</u>

• <u>luislandi.com</u>

Senior UX Designer with 9 years of experience in SaaS products. I like designing data visualization-rich platforms. My **achievements** include: Designed an **award-winning application**. Redesign a **data-visualization** platform that increased by 35% user satisfaction. Optimised the front-end **QA** highlighting 70% of bugs and usability issues before the release date. Reduced the **time to release** software by 10%.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## VERIZON CONNECT, Dublin, Ireland

October 2023-Now

Senior UX designer | verizonconnect.com

- Developed AI conversations to automate the highest volume of requests supported by the chatbot
- Redesigned the **Help Center** platform for improved navigation
- Optimised **billing system** and Auto Pay set-up process, resulting in reduced payment friction

## VSTAGE, Remote

February 2021-May 2023

Senior Product Designer | <u>luislandi.com/vstage</u>

- Led the creation of an online event management platform. Three worldwide events for **PayPal Global** with over 26k attendees over 24 hours.
- A visually appealing **white-labelled platform** that increases a 12% in the average of NPS results and a 12% improvement of the sense of trust.

## LEXIS NEXIS RISK SOLUTIONS, Dublin, Ireland

Sep 2019-Sep 2020

User Experience Lead | <u>luislandi.com/lexisnexis</u>

- I led the redesign of Map View a geospatial data visualization tool that helps insurers analyze environmental and peril risks.
- Improve **data visualization** for better interpretation of the risk, resulting in a 35% increase in user satisfaction.
- Increased the **risk assessment capabilities** by 24% and set up the system with seamless integration of diverse data sets in the future.
- Provided **actionable insight** to help the decision-making process resulting in a 12% reduction of the human analysis time.

## **ERICSSON**, Athlone, Ireland

Mar 2018-Sep 2019

Senior UX designer | <u>luislandi.com/ericsson</u>

- Created a dashboard-based portal to enable Ericsson's customers to monitor and manage their services.
- Implemented guerrilla usability test within the sprints and during an Expo Day with over 1200 attendees.

OTHERS JOB EXPERIENCE, Italy and Germany

May 2014 - Mar 2018

UX designer | linkedin.com/in/luislandi

## **EDUCATION**

Oct 2010 - Dec 2013

University of Padua, Padova, Italy Bachelor of Science in Psychology

#### **LANGUAGES**

Fluent in English, Italian, and Spanish.

Intermediate in German and Portuguese.